An immortal legend as you've only imagined.
Tarzan is a family, adventure, animation film directed by Chris Buck.
Tarzan was a small orphan who was raised by an ape
named Kala since he was a child.
He believed that this was his family, but on an
expedition Jane Porter is rescued by Tarzan.
He then finds out that he's human.
Now Tarzan must make the decision as to which family he should belong to...
Tarzan (voice), played by Tony Goldwyn.
Jane Porter (voice), played by Minnie Driver.
Kala (voice), played by Glenn Close.
Young Tarzan (voice), played by Alex D. Linz.
Terk (voice), played by Rosie O'Donnell.
Clayton (voice), played by Brian Blessed.
Tarzan is a 1999 American animated adventure comedy-drama film based on
the 1912 story Tarzan of the Apes by Edgar Rice Burroughs.
Produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation, it was directed by Kevin Lima and Chris Buck, from a screenplay by Tab Murphy, and
the writing team of Bob Tzudiker and Noni White, and is the first major animated film adaptation of the story.
Tony Goldwyn stars as the titular character, alongside Minnie
Driver, Glenn Close, Rosie O'Donnell, Alex D.
Linz, Brian Blessed, Nigel Hawthorne, Lance Henriksen, and Wayne Knight.
The film follows an orphan who is raised by the family of gorillas in
Africa, after his real parents were killed by a leopard.
Years later, he grows up into a man and meets other humans.
He is soon torn between the choice of leaving with
them or staying with his animal family.
Pre-production of Tarzan began in 1995, with Lima selected as
director and Buck joining him the same year.
Following Murphy's first draft, Tzudiker, White, Dave Reynolds, and Jeffrey Stepakoff (the latter two of whom received additional
screenplay credits in the final cut), were brought in to reconstruct the third act and add additional material to the screenplay.
English recording artist Phil Collins was recruited to compose and
record songs integrated with a score by Mark Mancina.
Meanwhile, the production team embarked on a research trip
to Uganda and Kenya to study the gorillas.
The animation of the film combines 2D hand-drawn animation with the extensive use of computer-generated imagery, and it was done in California, Orlando, and
Paris, with the pioneering computer animation software system Deep Canvas being predominantly used to create three-dimensional backgrounds.
Tarzan premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on June 12,
1999, and was released in the United States on June 18.
It received positive reviews from critics, who praised its voice
performances, music, animation, and action sequences.
Against a production budget of $130 million (then the most expensive traditionally animated film ever made until Treasure Planet in 2002), the film grossed $448.2 million worldwide, becoming the fifth highest-grossing
film of 1999, the second highest-grossing animated film of 1999 behind Toy Story 2, and the first Disney animated feature to open at first place at the North American box office since Pocahontas (1995).
It won the Academy Award for Best Original Song
("You'll Be in My Heart" by Phil Collins).
The film has led to many derived works, such as a Broadway adaptation, a television series,
and two direct-to-video followups, Tarzan & Jane (2002) and Tarzan II (2005).
Due to licensing issues with Edgar Rice Burroughs, Inc.,
the use of these characters is limited.
The film explores themes of baby, africa, gorilla, adoption, cartoon.
The tone is emotional.